<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>syPai</title>
    <description>Disciplined &amp; Relentless</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 23:55:09 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 23:55:09 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC [01], Week 1: coding.begin() </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first of the thirteen weeks has ended and I have started working
 on my project &lt;strong&gt;co-oCCur: High-speed subtitle synchronization&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Github  Repo: 
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sypai/co-oCCur&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
 sypai/co-oCCur
 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/GSoC-01-Week-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/GSoC-01-Week-1/</guid>
        
        
        <category>GSoC</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GSoC [00]: Bonding period ends &amp; Coding begins! </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A month-long community bonding period ended on 27 May,
commencing the official coding period. In this post, I would
like to share my GSoC 2019 community bonding experience
with CCExtractor Development, work-progress and the road
ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section-title margtop3rem&quot;&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;Community Bonding Period&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official list of selected proposals was released by Google
 on the 6th of May and with it started the community bonding
 period. It began with me &lt;em&gt;jumping for joy&lt;/em&gt; after getting the
 news of my proposal getting selected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was basically a month full of learning and planning.
 Two social groups have been created, one on Facebook
 and the other on Telegram, which includes over 600 selected
 students from around the globe. It is a great platform for
 sharing your progress and getting help when you are stuck
  somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the tasks I checked off during the community period!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deciding the structure of my project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is the first time I am going to be working on a project
 which involves so much! Deciding the structure of the project
early was a crucial task so that the development stays
smooth ahead. I was sure to use C++ as the language
and thus I started off with strengthening the concepts
of the language. After checking out some popular C++
projects and reading some blogs on the same I have
decided to use something like this:
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;img class=&quot;featured-image img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/project_structure.png&quot; alt=&quot;Structure Project&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating a Trello board&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As I had mentioned in my proposal I wanted to have a
detailed checklist of the tasks to be done with their deadlines.
This would help me and my mentor to keep track of my work.
 I am maintaining the milestones and deliverables in a
 Trello board, which can be found here : &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://trello.com/b/JQGOK4Yo/co-occursubtitlesynchronization&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
 Milestones and checklist for co-oCCur: High-speed subtitle synchronization tool
 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;img class=&quot;featured-image img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/trello_cooCCur.png&quot; alt=&quot;Trello Board&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting-up my Blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
For everyone to follow my progress on the project I have set
 up this blog. This is the best way for the whole community
to know what’s cooking.
It’s a simple and 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wowthemes.net/mediumish-free-jekyll-template/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
 mediumish
 &lt;/a&gt;
themed Jekyll blog hosted on
Github pages. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Here it resides: &lt;a href=&quot;https://sypai.github.io&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://sypai.github.io &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting-up Payoneer account&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There have been more discussions on this in the Telegram
 group than anything else. Fortunately, it took me around ten
 minutes to set it up and receive the confirmation email from
Payoneer.
 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;img class=&quot;featured-image img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/pay.png&quot; alt=&quot;Payoneer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Surprise &amp;#127873;  &amp;#128217; &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the CCExtractor’s website,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;primary left&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This year we're going to try something new. All
 accepted students will get a programming book
  immediately after being accepted, with the hope that they
  read them before the coding starts. We want to see
  if this increases the quality of the work.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the accepted students was to choose a technical
 book of their choice. I chose &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Elements of Programming
 Interviews in Python&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Adnan Aziz&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Tsung-Hsien Lee&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Amit Prakash&lt;/em&gt;. Placement season being next
 in the queue, this book is a very good addition to my
 library.
 &lt;br /&gt; Thank you &lt;a href=&quot;https://ccextractor.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CCExtractor Development!&lt;/a&gt; 😍
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
   &lt;img class=&quot;featured-image img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/book_CC.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Book&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Bad News &amp;#128531;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My end semester exams have been postponed, this was
 known, I had mentioned this in my proposal. But the final 
 schedule wasn’t announced until 20th May. Guess what! 
 Exams started from the very same day the coding period 
 officially began. 
 &lt;br /&gt;
I had to re-schedule the weekly milestones and deadlines.
 I have informed my mentor regarding this and he says,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;primary left&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;
as long as you are on track by the time of the first evaluation 
you're OK. But it would be a good idea to show me your
 progress often.
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be a bit of a predicament to manage to work with 
the exams. I hope by the end of first evaluation, I will able
 to complete all the deliverables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Road Ahead! &amp;#128739; &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the first four weeks, first evaluation [24 May - 28 May] begins.
 I will try to stick to the deadlines as I have mentioned in the 
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://trello.com/b/JQGOK4Yo/co-occursubtitlesynchronization&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
 trello &lt;/a&gt; 
 board. I know it is going to be a roller-coaster ride. I am sure I will learn a lot during the next 3 months!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish all the participants a fun and a productive summer. Happy Coding!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/GSoC-00-Bonding-period-ends-&-Coding-begins-!/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/GSoC-00-Bonding-period-ends-&-Coding-begins-!/</guid>
        
        
        <category>GSoC</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Google Summer of Code: And now my watch begins!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My proposal
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/projects/#5538361094176768&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;co-oCCur: High-speed subtitle synchronization&lt;/a&gt;
 has been accepted by 
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://ccextractor.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CCExtractor Development&lt;/a&gt;
 for Google Summer of Code (GSoC) 2019!
  &lt;br /&gt;
 I am thrilled to bits to spend my summer working with the “magicians” 
 behind the de-facto subtitle tool - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CCExtractor/ccextractor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CCExtractor&lt;/a&gt;.
 My mentor is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cfsmp3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Carlos Fernandez Sans &lt;/a&gt;(org admin, who originally built CCExtractor). What more could one ask for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section-title margtop3rem&quot;&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;About GSoC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put, it is an international annual program by Google aimed at promoting 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.com/resources/what-open-source&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
Open Source Software development &lt;/a&gt; 
among college and university students. Students apply for a project/idea of their choice to one of the many 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/organizations/?sp-page=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
Open Source Organizations&lt;/a&gt;
selected by Google, by submitting a proposal. Selected students spend their summer building the project by implementing what they proposed.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In return, the students gain excellent experience of building a real-world project, mentored by seasoned developers. The stipend 💰 and of course the bragging rights! 😎&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section-title margtop3rem&quot;&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;About my project&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;featured-image img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/GSoC_myProject.png&quot; alt=&quot;My Project on GSoC Website&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of the many ideas, present in the 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://ccextractor.org/public:gsoc:ideas_page_for_summer_of_code_2019&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CCExtractor’s GSoC page&lt;/a&gt;, 
I gravitated to
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://ccextractor.org/public:gsoc:highspeedsync&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Writing high-Speed subtitle synchronization tool&lt;/a&gt;.
After about a month of research on the same, I submitted my proposal on the 9th of April. 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1QEB3jDNvFVPP4OpvU1m_A3kME288LZKJVIs1g1AXin4/edit?usp=sharing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;
 is my accepted proposal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Closed_captioning&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Closed Captions (CC)&lt;/a&gt;
 and subtitles enhance audiovisual content by providing speech information and description of representative events in a textual format. 
 Captioning is especially used as an aid for people with hearing loss or deafness, but its use is definitely not limited to that domain.
 &lt;br /&gt; 
 For instance, it is frequently the case that captions are necessary to watch a TV show in a noisy surrounding or when one is not familiar 
 with the language or accent available in the audio streams.
 &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Downloading a subtitle document and playing it alongside an episode of your favourite TV show, is not rocket science, 
but it sure can feel that way sometimes. 
Getting the subtitle document that gives satisfactory synchronization on the first attempt is like hitting the jackpot.
 I know the annoyance that comes in with misaligned subtitles and is a very general problem. 
 &lt;br /&gt;
 For an ideal subtitle file, the subtitles are perfectly aligned with the base audiovisual content. In other words, the audio and the corresponding subtitles 
 &lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;co-oCCur&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.
 &lt;br /&gt;
The misalignment of the subtitle files is the underlying problem that this project aims to solve so that the viewer does not have any burden before the fun starts (this is what matters).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;featured-image img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/timeline.png&quot; alt=&quot;GSoC Timeline&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next 3 months, I will be working on this amazing project. I hope by the end of this summer the tool is ready to be used!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;primary right&quot;&gt;

&lt;em&gt;&quot;Every skill you acquire, doubles your odds of success&quot;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;
&lt;cite title=&quot;Source Title&quot;&gt;Scott Adams&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/Google-Summer-of-Code-And-now-my-watch-begins/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/Google-Summer-of-Code-And-now-my-watch-begins/</guid>
        
        
        <category>GSoC</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
